我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, i'm an ordinary forensic scientist.
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
But secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
但当我女儿从未来时空前来帮忙
But when my daughter came back from the future to help,
她改变了现在
she changed the present...
现在我们的世界比以往更加危险
and now our world is more dangerous than ever.
我是唯一一个来得及拯救世界的人
And I'm the only one fast enough to save it.
我是闪电侠
I am the Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
时间线是有延展性的
你的同伙是谁  诺拉
Who is your accomplice, Nora?
解药合成了  而且有效
The cure's finished, and it works.
-你做什么工作  -相信我
- What do you do? - Trust me.
如果我告诉你  你也不会相信的
You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
我们商量好了
We made an arrangement.
我们先治愈他  然后治愈格蕾丝
We cure him and then Grace.
这个新的时间线挣扎着想要冲破障碍
That is a new timeline struggling to break through.
重要的事即将到来
Something big is coming.
发生了什么
What's going on?
拜托
Please!
如果蝉不存在了
If Cicada doesn't exist anymore,
那又是谁
who was that?
我好想你  奥林叔叔
I've missed you, Uncle Orlin.
出现了差错
Something went wrong.
我们找到了德怀尔  我们给了他解药
We got Dwyer. We gave him the cure.
这明明应该结束了
This should all be over.
但是另一个蝉却出现了
But another Cicada showed up,
带走了德怀尔和匕首
took Dwyer and the dagger.
斯旺  你有在听我说话吗
Thawne! Did you hear what I said?
另一个蝉出现了
Another Cicada showed up.
我知道
I know.
这是谁
Who is that?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
你说操纵时间线可以阻止蝉
You said manipulating the timeline would stop Cicada.
你说你知道自己在干什么
You said you knew what you were doing!
我知道我说了什么
I know what I said.
我完全错了
I was very wrong.
我们该怎么办  我们现在该怎么办
What do we do? What do we do now?
我无法再帮助你了
I can't help you anymore...
小极速者
little runner.
什么
What?
你必须得帮助我
You have to help me.
一切都太晚了
It's too late.
不
No.
肯定还有别的办法
There's gotta be something we can do.
你  你必须帮助我
You--you have to help!
剩下能做的事只有一件
There is only one thing left to do.
告诉你爸爸
Tell your father.
你告诉他一切事情
You tell your father everything.
闪 电 侠
第五季
第十七集
你的肺部还在愈合
Your lung's healing.
等你恢复全部体力
It'll take a while for you to get
还需要一段时间
the rest of your strength back,
但不必担心
but don't worry.
我会照顾好你的
I'll take care of you.
就像你以前照顾我一样
Like you took care of me.
你是谁
Who are you?
格蕾丝
Grace?
你好  奥林叔叔
Hi, Uncle Orlin.
但你是
But you were--
一个昏迷的十岁女孩
A ten-year-old girl in a coma?
最终  那个医院里的女孩醒过来了
Eventually, that girl at the hospital wakes up.
她慢慢长大
She grows older,
然后她成为了我
and she becomes me.
你来自未来  就像闪电侠的女儿那样
You're from the future, like Flash's daughter.
我回来是为了和你再次合作
I came back here to work with you again.
我记得你教过我的所有东西  奥林叔叔
And I remember everything you taught me, Uncle Orlin.
好好休息
Now, get some rest.
慢着
Wait.
我们在哪里
Where are we?
我离开的期间  没有人能找到你
No one will find you while I'm gone.
如果你饿了  储藏柜里有面条
There's noodles in the pantry if you're hungry.
还有冰淇淋
And ice cream.
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
去处理一些重要的事情
To take care of something important.
等我回来时
When I get back...
我们一起想办法如何恢复你的超能力
We're gonna figure out how you get your powers back.
医疗
中心
安布勒斯医生从来没有提起过
And Dr. Ambres never talked about
她和奥林·德怀尔之间的关系吗
her relationship with Orlin Dwyer?
她平时也不怎么说话
She never really talked about anything.
自从她的未婚夫去世后
After her fiancé died,
她就变得跟以前不太一样
she wasn't quite the same.
怎么说
How so?
愤怒  沉默寡言
Angry. Withdrawn.
她唯一看起来高兴是在
Only time she seemed happy
和那个昏迷的女孩一起的时候
was when she was with that girl in the coma.
你能想到什么可以帮助我们找到德怀尔吗
Can you think of anything that might help us find Dwyer?
我很抱歉  警探
I'm sorry, Detective.
好吧  你如果想到什么
Okay, if you come up with anything,
请打给我  好吗
would you give me a call, please?
谢谢你
Thank you.
肯定有人知道点什么
Somebody's gotta know something.
我们找过的人说的都是实话
Everyone we've talked to is telling the truth.
我认为安布勒斯是唯一一个和德怀尔合作的人
I think Ambres was the only one working with Dwyer.
我们回中城警局再仔细看一下档案
Well, look, we'll pore over the files at CCPD.
也许我们漏了些什么
Maybe we missed something.
如果我们有发现  会通知你们的
We'll let you know if we come up with anything, all right?
你还好吗
You okay?
我只是
I just, uh...
不知道该怎么做
don't know what to do.
我也是
Yeah, me neither.
但是我们以前也碰过壁
We've hit walls before, though.
我们会想到办法的
We'll figure it out.
翻译进度             分析进度
舌尖音语言学翻译  完成
翻译
好
All right.
诺拉·韦斯特·艾伦  来看看你有什么秘密
Nora West-Allen, let's see what we have here.
无趣  无趣  无趣
Boring. Boring. Boring.
依然无趣  无趣  无趣
Banality. Boring. Boring.
不是吧
Come on.
我知道你有同伙  却没有名字
I know you're working with someone, but no names.
翻译
聪明的姑娘
Clever girl.
表层是不会自动清理干净的
Cortex isn't gonna clean itself, you know.
桌子不错嘛   在享受新装备
Oh, nice table. Liking the new digs.
严格来说  这些是以前的东西
Well, technically, they're old digs,
看来在遇袭后  好的一面是可以重新装修
but I guess there is an upside to remodeling after an attack.
你们有什么发现吗
Did you guys find anything?
我发布了一篇文章
Well, I put out an article,
但我所有的读者都没有见过德怀尔
but none of my readers have seen Dwyer
或是这个新的蝉
or this new Cicada.
我找过厄尔·考克斯和我所有的线人
I talked to Earl Cox, all my contacts...
毫无线索
nothing.
卫星还有多久能扫描暗物质
How long till the satellite can scan for dark matter?
现在就可以
How about now?
前提是这个新蝉身上有可追踪的暗物质才行
Well, if this new Cicada even has traceable dark matter.
我们见过蝉二代做过一些
I mean, we've seen Cicada numéro deux do things
我们没见过的事
that we've not seen before, right?
是的  他能抑制超能力
Yeah, I mean, he can dampen powers,
他能像德怀尔一样控制那把匕首
he can control the dagger just like Dwyer,
但  我不确定  又像是...
but it's-- I don't know, it's also like...
像是他还能控制我们
Like he could take control of us.
希望凯特琳能在唐怀瑟站点查出个究竟
Let's hope Caitlin can figure that out at the Tannhauser site
同时我们要找出他的下落
while we figure out where he is.
翻译实验室档案馆
已侦测到11578
科林斯森林
科林斯森林实验室档案馆有物品发出警报
We got a Starchives asset in Kolins Woods.
实验室档案馆物品
已侦测到11578
科林斯森林
实验室档案馆是什么
Starchives? What is this?
那是我们存放所有和闪电侠相关物品的地方
Well, it's a place where we house everything Flash related--
模型  超级战衣
prototypes, super suits--
从第一天开始的所有东西
I mean, everything since day one.
警报响了  是因为...
Okay, and the alarm is going off because...
因为有人刚刚偷了我们的东西
Because somebody just stole something from us.
一件非常危险的东西
Something really, really, not good.
你们到实验室档案馆了没
You guys at the Starchives yet?
我们刚到
We just got here.
没有破门而入的迹象
No sign of forced entry.
显然也没有顶灯照明
Or overhead lighting, apparently.
天花板上肯定是个吸尘器
Pretty sure that's a vacuum.
继续检查
Okay, keep looking!
再和我说一次  我们在找什么
Remind me again what we're looking for?
就像一个巨大的圆形玻璃气泡
Uh, it's like a huge round glass bubble.
你是说那个吗
You mean like that?
-没错  我们找到了  -我们找到了
- Yeah-- We found it! - We found it!
斯旺的时间球  你确定吗
Thawne's Time Sphere? Are you sure?
-什么叫做"我确定吗"  -非常肯定
- What do you mean "Am I sure?" - Pretty sure.
它就在我眼前  为什么这么问
I'm looking right at it, why?
因为它也在我们眼前
'Cause we're looking right at it too.
时间球同时出现在这里和实验室档案馆里吗
So it's here and in the Starchives at the same time?
有人偷走了构造图  然后造了一个复制品吗
Somebody stole the plans and made a duplicate?
不好说
Not exactly.
各位  准备行动  开始同步分析
Guys, cue up Operation: Shazam.
准备好了
Ready.
两个时间球都有一个同样的刮痕
One scratch on two different Time Spheres.
或是同一个时间球上有同一个刮痕
Or one scratch on one Time Sphere.
这是不可能的  除非
That's impossible... unless--
除非它们是同一个
Unless it's the same one.
的确是同一个
It is the same one.
这就是我们的时间球
This is our Time Sphere.
出现在这里  而同一时间
Which shows up here at the same time
一个类似蝉的人掳走了奥林·德怀尔
that someone who looks like Cicada kidnaps Orlin Dwyer.
这不是巧合
It's not a coincidence.
所以无论是谁掳走了德怀
So whoever kidnapped Dwyer--
他是来自未来的蝉
Is the Cicada from the future.
你再动  我就开枪
You move, I shoot.
愚蠢的举动
That was dumb.
是他对吧
It was him, wasn't it?
另外一个蝉
The other Cicada.
他不知道打中他的是什么
Guy didn't know what hit him.
你说他在找一件悬案的文档
You said he was after a cold case file?
-这些文档有存入电脑吗  -还没
- Are any of them digitized? - Not yet.
但唯一能找出不见文档的办法
But the only way to figure out what's missing
就是看看剩下的有什么
is to see what's still here.
我...
I mean...
我可以帮忙找
I could help with that.
好了  大家都出去吧
All right, everybody. Clear out.
鉴证员要调查现场
CSI needs this scene.
话说
Hey, by the way,
这也许是我们唯一的线索
this might not be our only lead.
你记得我们帮斯旺做的时间球吗
Do you remember that Time Sphere that we built for Thawne?
那个巨大的仓鼠球吗
That big hamster ball thing?
有人在未来偷了一个来到这里
Someone stole one in the future to come here.
为了什么  我们那个蝉的模仿者吗
For what, our-our Cicada copycat?
符合逻辑
It makes sense.
我不敢相信我刚说了这话
I can't even believe I just said that.
-好了  儿子  该你了  -好
- Okay, son, you're on. - Yup.
好  我查看了所有文档
Okay, I went through everything.
确实有一个文件失踪
There was indeed one file missing.
那是  谢谢  2017年的
And it's--thank you-it is from 2017.
就这些了
That's it.
好的  我去调查下
All right, I'll do some digging,
看看这案子到底为何如此重要
see why this was so important,
他们要在墙上凿个洞来偷它
they had to cut a hole in the wall.
我来帮忙
I'll help.
你确定想要这么做吗
Are you sure you want to do this?
我是说  这可是件大事
I mean, this is a big deal.
就像是"不是佩妮的船"那样的大事
Like, "Not Penny's boat" knd of big deal.
出自《迷失》第三季结局的梗
好吧
Okay.
卡米拉·黄  你和我正式...
Kamilla Hwang, you and I are officially...
"交往中"
"In a Relationship."
-社交媒体正式公布  -是吧
- Social media official! - What!
拉里  照旧
Larry, my usual.
我叫杰森
It's Jason.
拉尔夫  怎么...
Ralph! What's, um--
你来这里做什么
what are you doing here?
和你一样
Same as you
从拯救世界中休息一下
taking a break from saving the old world.
看看你俩
Look at you two.
年轻的情侣
Young love.
那么  小卡  你什么时候见见团队
So, uh, K-Dawg, when you gonna meet the group?
团队
Uh, the group?
是啊  小队  队伍  团伙
Yeah, the squad, the team. The gang.
我们这里正在约会之中呢
Uh, hey, we're actually in the middle of a date here.
其实我们的约会刚结束了  宝贝
Actually, we're at the end of a date, babe.
-我有那个活要去  -对对
- I have that gig. - Oh, right.
你复活节那事  你得走了
Your Easter thing. You have to go.
-她得走了  -西斯科
- She has to go. - Oh, uh, Cisco?
我是来告诉你巴里想和你谈谈
I'm supposed to tell you that Barry wanted to talk to you.
或许应该直接发个短信
Probably could've texted that.
是啊  应该啊
Yeah, probably.
好吧  复活节兔子的照片
Okay, well, Easter Bunny photos
不会自己凭空出现
aren't gonna take themselves.
这个是比较低端的摄影师工作
It's kind of a bottom-of-the-barrel photography gig,
但你总得从某个地方开始  对吧
but gotta start somewhere, right?
-完全没错  -除了这里哪里都行
- Totally. - Anywhere but here.
-不如我送你出去吧  -好的
- Why don't I walk you out? - Oh, okay.
该死的  拉瑞
Damn it, Larry!
我还是叫杰森
Still Jason!
看呀  看呀  看呀
Voilà, voilà, voilà.
我们来看看这里是什么
Let's see what we have here.
斯旺的时间球
Thawne's Time Sphere.
你在做什么  歇洛克
What are you doing, Sherloque?
[法语]
我在追寻一个新的线索
Well, I'm pursuing a new lead
找出这个神秘的蝉的身份
to identify the mystery Cicada.
如果你需要关于时间球的信息
Well, if you needed information about the Time Sphere,
开口问就是了
you could've just asked.
是没错  但是记忆可能会有误差
That's right, but memory can be deceiving.
尤其是对于普通人类来说
Especially for a regular human.
不  我更喜欢源头信息
No, I prefer a primary source.
那这个新线索
And this new lead,
你昨晚是不是也在追
were you pursuing it last night too?
-没错  -还有整个上周末
- That's right. - And all last weekend?
没错
That's right.
我很努力的想要找...
I am working very hard to get...
找到我想要的
to get what I want.
时间线是有延展性的
乔查到了新蝉拿走的文件
Joe traced the file that our new Cicada took.
两年前发生了一个超能力者袭击案
There was a meta attack here two years ago.
两个人死了  但超能力者身份一直不明
Two people died, and the meta was never ID'd.
所以这个新蝉也许在找这个超能力者
So this new Cicada might be going after this meta?
好吧
Okay.
让我震波什么
What do I vibe?
我们还不确定
Well, we're not exactly sure.
所有街头摄像机都被爆炸摧毁了
All the street cameras were destroyed by the explosion.
原本的取款机坏到无法提取数据
The original ATM was too fried to recover any data.
-真的吗  -是啊
- For real? - Yeah.
那我走了
Well, I'm out.
我没法震波一个不存在的犯罪现场
I can't vibe a crime scene that does not exist.
字面意义上的不存在
Literally does not exist.
即便是这个取款机  也是全新的
I mean, even this ATM is, like, brand-spanking-new.
但这墙壁不是
But this concrete isn't.
上边还有烧焦的痕迹
It still has scorch marks on it.
帮我拿着
Hold this.
亲爱的  你忘了你的银行卡
Sweetie! You forgot your ATM card.
你看到了什么
What'd you see?
受害者们
The victims.
他们是格蕾丝·吉本斯的父母
They were Grace Gibbons' parents.
在格蕾丝的脑中  她把自己看做蝉
In Grace's mindscape, she saw herself as Cicada.
然后另一个蝉出现找寻她父母的杀手
And another Cicada shows up targeting her parents' killer.
肯定是她了
It has to be her.
新蝉是格蕾丝·吉本斯
The new Cicada is Grace Gibbons.
从未来而来
From the future.
时间旅行真讨厌
Time travel sucks.
格蕾丝  出什么事了
Grace, what's wrong?
看看这个
Look at this.
你父母的谋杀档案
It's your parents' murder file?
你看到他们做了些什么吗
Do you see what they did?
什么都没做
Nothing!
三个证人看到一个穿着兜帽衫的女人
Three witnesses saw a woman in a hoodie
离开现场  但是中城警局精英们
leave the scene, but did Central City's finest
有没有派出搜查队或是通缉令呢
put out a search party or an APB?
没有  他们觉得这是闪电侠的活
No. They thought it sounded like a job for the Flash.
你看这个现场留下的残骸
Look at this debris from the scene.
像是化学灼烧形成的
Looks like a chemical burn.
不是化学灼伤
It's not a chemical burn.
这是烧焦的暗物质残留
It's charred dark matter residue.
我们可以查到是哪个超能力者留下的
We can track the meta who left it.
怎么查
How?
我没法查到准确的实时位置
I can't track an exact real time location,
但可以很接近
but I can get close.
找到她了
Found her.
格蕾丝  你在干什么
Grace, what are you doing?
在我们那个时代  他们的瘟疫
In the time I'm from, their plague spreads
传遍了全世界  势不可挡
across the world, unchecked, unabated.
但如今我回到现在跟你一起
But now that I'm here with you,
我们能改变局面
we can change that.
成功完成任务
And the mission can succeed.
什么任务
What mission?
我们的任务
Ours.
杀死所有超能力者
To kill every last meta-human.
就从那个杀害我父母的混蛋开始
Starting with the rat bastard who killed my parents.
那么  第二代蝉就是未来的格蕾丝
So, Cicada II is really Grace from the future,
她想找那个杀害她父母的超能力者复仇
and she's trying to get revenge on the meta
而那个超能力杀手就在这里吗
that murdered her parents and that killer meta is here?
西斯科看到了取款机最后输入的个人识别密码
Cisco saw the last PIN that was entered into the ATM.
卡的主人是薇琪·博兰和约翰·博兰
The card belongs to Vickie and John Bolen.
我们已经去过他们家了
We already went by their house,
一个邻居说他们在开派对
and a neighbor said they were having a party here.
应该就是那两个人
Um, I think this is them.
打扰一下  先生
Excuse me, sir?
乔·韦斯特侦探  中城警局
Detective Joe West, we're from CCPD.
你是约翰·博兰先生吗
Are you Mr. John Bolen?
是的  有什么事吗
I am. How can I help you?
怎么了
What's going on? Oh.
不好意思
Sorry to be rude,
我们在开派对
but we're in the middle of a party.
不会耽误太久
This won't take long. Um...
你记得自己在2017年5月4号使用过
Do you remember using an ATM on Kingswell and 42nd
金斯维尔街和42街路口的自动取款机吗
around May 4th, 2017?
那天发生了一场爆炸
There was an explosion that day.
我们认为这事涉及一位超能力者
We think a meta-human might have been involved.
亲爱的  你和爱丽丝去把孩子们叫到一块
Hon, why don't you and Alice start gathering
拍张合照吧
the kids for a team photo?
我来跟这些警官谈
I'll talk to the nice officers.
好
Okay.
事情过去这么久了  你们竟然还能找到我
I can't believe you found me after all this time.
我们想知道那天发生了什么
We'd just like to know what happened that day.
你引爆了自动取款机吗
Did you blow up that ATM?
我...  事情发生得太快了
I-it all happened so fast.
我碰到了机器
I touched the machine,
然后我就感觉体内好像有什么被激活了
and it was like something turned on in me.
你极大地加速了取款机里的分子运动
You hyper-accelerated the molecules in the ATM,
造成了剧烈的链式反应
causing a violent chain reaction.
我只记得我看到火苗就跑了
I just know I saw sparks and ran.
然后就听到了爆炸声
Then I heard this explosion
钱飞得到处都是
and money was flying everywhere.
看上去就像我在抢银行
It looked like I was trying to rob the bank.
我不敢回去
I was too afraid to go back.
至少没人受伤
At least no one got hurt.
博兰女士  我们有理由相信
Mrs. Bolen, we have reason to believe
有人想杀你
a killer is targeting you.
为什么
Why?
因为你的...  超能力
It's because of your... abilities.
我们希望你能接受联邦政府的保护
Listen, we'd like to put you in federal protection
来保证你家人的安全
to keep your family safe.
那我要怎么跟我丈夫说
And what would I tell my husband?
还有我女儿
Or my daughter?
"抱歉  妈妈有超能力"
"Hey, sorry, Mommy has powers."
我们都不得不放弃现在的正常生活
We all have to leave our lives behind.
他们不知道你的超能力吗
They don't know about your powers?
当然不知道  没人知道
Of course not. No one does.
你觉得我很为此骄傲吗
You think I'm proud of this?
我觉得他们有权利知道事实
I think they have a right to know the truth.
他们是你的家人
They're your family.
你们又算什么人
And who the hell do you think you are,
需要你们教我怎么做吗
telling me what to do?
我们哪里都不去
We're not going anywhere.
话说完了
That's final.
请离开吧
Please leave.
她处境危险  我们留下观察
She's not safe. We're staying put.
我收到你的信息了  什么急事
I got your text. What's the emergency?
好  仔细听我说
Okay. Listen to me very carefully.
我暂时不去管连环杀手绑架犯的案子
I took a break from serial killer kidnapper madness
去做了一件了不起的事情
to do something awesome.
我有了新的职业规划
So I decided on a new career path.
我一直对摄影感兴趣
Photography was always my passion,
我就想  那我为什么不做摄影工作呢
and I figured why not make it my job?
照片拍得很好  卡米拉
These are great, Kamilla.
我对她有了蜘蛛侠式启发
I Peter Parker'd her.
德比  我们私谈
Dibs, sidebar.
私谈
Sidebar?
对  私谈  快点
Sidebar, now!
你对她有了...  蜘蛛侠式启发
You have, uh... Peter Parker'd her.
我的意思是  卡米拉既然摄影这么厉害
Yeah, I mean, Kamilla is a great photographer
我想她可以给爱瑞丝做摄影工作
and I thought she could start taking some pictures for Iris,
这样她可能就会常来尖端实验室
and then maybe she'd start to come around S.T.A.R. Labs.
运气好的话  她也许会被
I don't know, if we're lucky, get bitten
什么放射性的东西咬上一口
by something radioactive.
变成个什么蜘蛛人
Become, like, a Spider-Person.
你这么想的时候  有没有意识到
So, while you thought, did it occur to you
根本没人叫你这么干
that no one asked you to do this?
你觉得她当不了蜘蛛人吗
You don't think she'd make a good Spider-Person?
你给我认真听好了
You listen to me and you listen good,
你这个跳梁小丑
you turkey on stilts.
不需要你多管闲事
It is not your job
把我女朋友弄进团队里
to get my girlfriend on the team!
-伙计们  -两位好
- Hey, guys. - Hey, you two!
我看见你俩在里面聊得挺开心
You guys are getting along in there, I see that.
啥事啊
What's going on?
你的朋友爱瑞丝
Your friend Iris was actually
给我找了一份摄影的活
just giving me a photography gig.
是件小差事  不过卡米拉答应
Well, it's small, but Kamilla has agreed to shoot
在这周末的航路游行里为《中城市民》拍摄
the Fairway parade for the "Citizen" this weekend.
不是吧
Shut the front door.
太难以置信了
That is unbelievable.
恭喜  这太棒了
Congrats. That's amazing.
我俩何不去喝点东西庆祝一下
Hey, why don't you and I go, uh, drink and celebrate?
当然好  我迟些发信息给你
Oh, sure. Um, I will text you later.
那太棒了  谢谢
Yes, that sounds great. Thank you.
-可以走了吗  -是的
- You ready? - Yeah.
好吧  好吧
Well, well, well.
你好  艾尔伯德·斯旺
Bonjour, Eobard Thawne.
如果我是艾尔伯德·斯旺
If I am Eobard Thawne,
我会是一个什么样的人呢
what kind of man am I?
有耐心  对吗
Patient, right?
科学大师
Master of science.
但同时
But also...
也是一个
a master of...
诡计大师
subterfuge.
因为我
Because not only...
不仅仅是
am I...
艾尔伯德·斯旺
Eobard Thawne,
同时我也是
but I'm also...
哈里森·威尔斯博士
Dr. Harrison Wells.
而那个人
And that man...
那个人会把自己的秘密藏在...
that man would keep his secrets...
身边
...close.
看看我们找到了什么
What have we here?
太好了
Well, well, well.
你好啊
Bonjour.
薇琪怎么会不知道她杀了两个人
How could Vickie not know she killed two people?
中城曾经有段时间
There was a time in Central City
不是所有的超能力者袭击都为众人所知
where not all meta attacks were public knowledge.
为什么不  人们有权知晓
Why not? I mean, people should know--
前市长贝洛斯
Former Mayor Bellows...
试图把一些事情对媒体隐瞒
...tried to keep certain things out of the media.
他说他不想制造恐慌
Said he didn't want to create a panic.
结果发现他让超能力者为他工作
Turns out he had metas on the payroll.
他只是不想引起注意
Didn't want the heat.
塞西尔的电话  我一会回来
That's Cecile. I'll be right back.
你想错了  你知道吗
You were wrong, you know.
什么事
About what?
关于薇琪不想把她有超能力的事
About Vickie not wanting to tell her family
告诉她的家人
about her abilities.
那是她做出的决定
It's her choice not to tell them.
对她的家人隐瞒这样的秘密
Look, keeping a secret like that
是非常危险的
from her family is-- it's dangerous.
他们可能会受到伤害  可能更糟
I mean, they might get hurt or worse.
她只是想保护他们
She's just trying to protect them.
我能理解  真的  但是
I get that, I do, but...
我也曾认为为他人利益着想
I-I used to think that keeping secrets from people
而对他们隐瞒实情是高尚的决定
for their own good was a noble decision,
那样会保护到他们
that it would protect them.
但其实当你那样做时  你剥夺了他们
But when you do that, you just rob those people
为自己做决定的权力
from making their own decisions.
我甚至对你也这样做过
I even did it with you.
就是你不愿带我回到你的过去的时候
Like when you didn't want to take me to your past.
我不想你看见
I didn't want you to see how painful
我作为闪电侠有多么痛苦
things got for me as the Flash
或者让你妈妈多为难
or how bad things got for your mom.
因为秘密就像一堵墙
But secrets are like walls, and...
隔着一堵墙  你不可能真正了解一个人
you can't really know someone with walls between you.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我肯定连接到了格蕾丝的意识
I must have connected to Grace's mind.
她就要来了
She's coming.
格蕾丝要来了
Grace is coming.
我没找到蝉  你呢
I don't see Cicada anywhere. Do you?
是闪电侠
It's the Flash!
妈  你为派对请了闪电侠和XS的扮装者吗
Mom, you got Flash and XS cosplayers for the party?
没错  我就是闪电侠  我超喜欢
Yes, I am the Flash! And I love...
足球  你们大家喜欢足球吗
soccer, do you guys love soccer?
你们想...  对啊  棒极了
Do you want to-- yeah, or--awesome!
跟我来
Come with me!
我们来这边踢足球
Here, let's play some soccer over here.
这边  这边  快来  跟上
This way. This way. Come on, come on, come on.
帮我疏散孩子们  快跟我来
Help me with the kids. Come on, come on!
离那边远远的
Far away from there.
-怎么回事  -蝉要来这里了
- What's going on? - Cicada is coming here.
-什么  -就现在
- What? - Now.
我们能把大家都转移离开这里
We can move everyone else out of here,
但你和你的家人得跟我来
but you and your family have to come with me.
好的
All right.
-杀人犯  -格蕾丝  住手
- Murderer. - Grace, stop.
她是无辜的  那是个意外
She's innocent. It was an accident.
诺拉  这世上不存在意外
There are no accidents, Nora.
薇琪
Vickie?
-我们得帮妈妈  -爱丽丝
- We have to help Mom. - Alice!
爱丽丝  不
Alice, no!
爱丽丝
Alice!
我的神速力恢复了
My speed's back.
我们得带他们离开这
We need to get them out of here.
我会找到你的
I'll find you.
我不敢相信里面那个小姑娘
I can't believe that little girl in there
长大之后变成了时间旅行连环杀手
grows up to be a time-traveling serial killer.
为什么我们现在不直接叫醒她
Why can't we just wake her up right now?
我们之前试过  没有用
We tried before. It didn't work.
你们之前研究的超能力者解药呢
What about the meta cure y'all cooked up?
我们需要征得格蕾丝的同意
We'd need Grace's consent.
而且凯特琳也说她的身体太脆弱了
Besides, Caitlin says that her condition
连尝试的可能都没有
is too fragile to even try.
我猜是因为毁掉了时间旅行仓鼠球
And I'm assuming that destroying the time-traveling hamster ball,
把时间线搅乱了
that messes up the timeline?
对  可能把事情搅得更糟糕了
Yeah, it would probably just make things even worse.
-天呐  -怎么了
- God! - What's wrong?
她的思想
Her mind.
和之前攻击尖端科研实验室的
It's exactly the same as the Cicada
那个蝉一模一样
that attacked us at S.T.A.R. Labs.
天呐  里面满满的只有仇恨
Oh, my God, it's filled with nothing but hatred.
诺拉进入格蕾丝的大脑时发现
Nora found out when she went into Grace's mind
格蕾丝能听见德怀尔  在昏迷状态里也可以
that Grace could hear Dwyer, even in her coma--
他的愤怒  他的怒意
his anger, his rage.
她在听
She was listening.
她能继承他的工作
She can carry out his words.
兄弟们
Hey, guys.
爱丽丝清醒过来了  她没事了
Alice is back from the OR and she's okay,
但是她的父母情况非常不好
but her parents are really not.
薇琪  我让你离开
Vickie, I asked you to leave!
她是我女儿
She's my daughter.
不  我想要爸爸
No. I want my dad.
看不出来她怕你吗
Can't you see that she's terrified of you?
她差点被害死了
She could've been killed!
我是想要保护你们
I was trying to protect you guys.
用撒谎的方式吗  你是个超能力者  薇琪
By lying? You're a meta, Vickie!
人形定时炸弹
A human time bomb!
你怎么能瞒着我们
How do you keep that from us?
博兰先生  先缓一缓
Mr. Bolen... let's take a breath.
咱们去外面吧
Let's step outside.
我们做了正确的事情
We did the right thing.
保护了这家人的安全
We kept this family safe.
那为什么感觉所有事情都变得更糟了
Then why does it feel like we made everything so much worse?
需要我帮你
Need any help with that, uh--
不
Nope.
除非你是来捣乱的
Unless you came here to break something,
那样你可是绝佳人选
in which case you'd be the perfect candidate.
是我活该
I deserve that.
我不该掺和卡米拉的事情
Never should've interfered with Kamilla.
有时候我会忘了
Sometimes, I forget how...
我有多让人难堪
embarrassing I can be.
我不是因你感到难堪  也不是因为
I'm not embarrassed by you, and I'm not embarrassed
闪电侠小队里的任何人感到难堪
by anyone on Team Flash.
你们是我的家人  问题不在你们
You guys are my family. You're not the problem.
这才是问题  这才是问题
This is the problem. This is the problem.
卡米拉沉浸在幸福里  完全没注意到
Kamilla is blissfully unaware
尖端科研实验室里疯狂的事情
of any of the madness that goes on in S.T.A.R. Labs,
或是我们从超能力者手里拯救这座城市的日常
or that we routinely save the city from evil metas.
或是你有个秘密身份
Or that you have a secret identity
穿着皮衣耍着花招
and dress up in leather and go all pew-pew!
尤其是皮衣
Especially the leather.
我和她  相处得很好
She and I, we got a good thing.
和别人在一起从来没有这种
And being with somebody has never felt so...
轻松的感觉
so easy.
只要我一和她在一起
And when I'm with her, for once,
我感觉自己就是个普通人
I just feel like a normal dude,
过着平凡的生活
with a normal life
我的社交媒体官宣女朋友
and a social-media-official girlfriend,
恰巧是个拍照达人
who happens to be a very talented photographer
而不是个  蜘蛛人
and not... a Spider-Person.
这很不错  真的
It's--that's amazing, man. It really is.
我保证我会尊重这件事
And I promise that I will respect that.
但是我要问你  你觉得
But I gotta ask, how long do you think
你能把这两个世界分开多久
you can keep those two worlds separate?
我妈妈和一个叫克雷格的人在一起过
Look... my mom dated this guy, Craig,
克雷格是个税务会计师也是个斗牛士
and Craig was a tax accountant and a freelance bull rider.
一直把这两个世界分得很开
Never let one world know about the other, and...
让他饱受折磨
it just tore him up.
给他带来的痛苦比那些牛还多
More than those bulls ever did.
我真的该去工作了
I should definitely be working.
重点是  我知道你为什么害怕
Look, the thing is, I get why you're afraid
失去你和卡米拉拥有的这一切
of losing what you have with Kamilla,but
但是如果你不让她进入这个世界
if you keep her out of this world...
在我看来
it seems to me that you're always
你的一部分总是关闭的
gonna be turning off a part of yourself.
这样不对
That's not right.
如果克雷格没有意外地
And if Craig hadn't been crushed to death
被文件柜砸死
by that huge filing cabinet...
我知道他一定会有同样的感受
I know he'd feel the same way.
我没能杀掉她
I didn't get her.
也许这是件好事
Well, maybe that's a good thing,
这份文件我看过了  完全讲不通
'cause I've read this file and it doesn't make sense.
格蕾丝  案发现场的钱没被拿走
Grace, there was no money taken from the crime scene.
我觉得你父母的遭遇
I think what happened to your mom and dad
可能是场意外
might've been an accident.
她杀了我的父母  奥林叔叔
She killed my parents, Uncle Orlin!
那不是场意外
It wasn't an accident!
你和他们语气一样
You sound like them.
你为什么会和他们说的一样
Why do you sound like them?
格蕾丝你的头
Grace, your head.
我得带你去看安布勒斯医生
We gotta get you to Dr. Ambres.
她知道该怎么帮你
She'll know how to help.
她谁都不帮  再也帮不了了
She's not helping anyone. Not anymore.
为什么
Why not?
我把她杀了
I killed her.
但是安布勒斯医生救了你
But Dr. Ambres saved your life.
同时也毁了你
And destroyed yours.
你被赋予了神力
You had a gift.
一个从天而降的武器为你所用
An unbreakable weapon that fell from the sky for you to use.
只有你能控制
For you to control.
然后她把你的能力夺走了
And she took that power away from you.
不  格蕾丝
No, Grace.
我想要那个解药
I wanted that cure.
而且我也希望你使用它
And I wanted you to have it too.
不  那是不可能的
No. No, that's impossible.
我们本该并肩作战的
We were supposed to do this together.
格蕾丝  我只是想让你开心
Grace, I just wanted you to be happy.
这是我一直想要的全部
That's all I ever wanted.
我爱你  格蕾丝  你是我的家人
I love you, Grace. You're my family.
你会不惜一切去救我  是吧
And you'd do anything to save me, right?
我知道我该干什么了
I know what I have to do.
格蕾丝  停下
Grace, stop.
格蕾丝  不要这样  格蕾丝  求你了
Grace, stop! Grace, please!
晚上好  威尔斯博士
Good evening, Dr. Wells.
你好  吉迪恩
Bonjour, Gideon.
我相信我有一个东西...
I believe I have something that belongs...
属于这里
right here.
视频日志  条目247
Video log, entry 247.
我一直在纠结于
I have long struggled
时间易变的特性
with time's insistence on change.
一个变量就可以改变时间线
One variable changes the timeline.
我们的记忆也一同改变  并不知晓
Our memories are changed too, without any knowledge
其他可能的情况  但是再也不是这样了
of time's other possibilities, but not anymore.
他这是要搞什么
Where he is going with this?
就像人是由DNA组成的一样
Just as the human body is made up of DNA,
同样  多元宇宙是否也是由
so, too, is the multiverse made up
它独特的源代码的
of its own unique source code.
一个无法被篡改的代码
One that cannot be altered.
不管你是从哪个时间线来
No matter what timeline you're in.
直到现在
Until now,
因为我破译了这个代码
because I have cracked that code.
所以时间线  尽管它容易被改变
And so the timeline, it can be malleable,
但是我的知识...
but my knowledge...
牢固不变
will be intractable.
吉迪恩  暂停视频日志
Gideon, freeze video log.
捕捉透明板上的文字
Capture the clear board.
与手写样本二号做对比
Run against handwriting sample number two.
诺拉·韦斯特·艾伦的日志
The journal of Nora West-Allen.
分析字迹中
分析完成  确认字迹与
Analysis complete, handwriting match
匹配           成功
哈里森·威尔斯相符
for Harrison Wells confirmed.
就这些吗  威尔斯博士
Will that be all, Dr. Wells?
是的  吉迪恩
Yes, Gideon.
就这些
That will be all.
这就是我为什么没告诉你我的超能力
And that's why I didn't tell you about my powers.
我觉得对你来说很难接受
I thought it would be too hard for you.
但是你很坚强
But you're tough.
比我任何时候都坚强
Tougher than I've ever been.
或许你可以再替我坚强一下
So maybe you can be tough for me too?
她们是和谐的一家
They're a good family.
跟你说她们可以搞定的
Told you they'd figure it out.
爸...
Dad...
我有些事要跟你讲
I need to tell you something.
宝贝  怎么了
Oh, baby, what's wrong?
格蕾丝的思想
Grace's mind.
越来越强烈了
Oh, it's getting so much stronger.
急诊部
她来了
She's here.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
薇琪·博兰
Vickie Bolen!
把自己交出来
Give yourself over to me,
不然你老公就死了
or your husband dies.
这个蝉不在乎那个人是不是超能力者
This Cicada doesn't care if someone's a meta or not.
她会杀掉挡她的任何人
She'll kill anyone who stands in her way.
XS  在蝉再次扔匕首之前快把她带走
XS, get her out of here before Cicada tries that again.
不要减速
Do not slow down.
警探  我们需要将她带到安全的地方
Detective, we need to get her somewhere safe.
-妈妈  -没有爱丽丝我不走
- Mom? - I'm not leaving without Alice.
你才是目标  博兰女士
You're the target, Mrs. Bolen.
她不跟着你会更安全
She's safer without you.
来吧  我们走
Come on, now, let's go.
来  亲爱的  我们带你去安全的地方
Come on, sweetie, let's get you somewhere safe.
XS  快走
XS, go!
-怎么样了  -我们有个紧急情况
- What do you got? - Well, we have a situation.
其实是两个
Or two, actually.
那个是新的蝉
So that's the new Cicada,
然后这个匕首正在追诺拉和博兰女士
and that's the dagger chasing Nora and Ms. Bolen.
-各位  我需要帮忙  -该行动了
- Guys, I need help! - Time to move.
格蕾丝
Grace.
放他走
Let him go.
我知道你要为你的父母复仇  但是
I know you want revenge for your parents, but--
但这不是那个女人的错
But it wasn't that woman's fault.
那也改变不了他们都死了的事实
That doesn't change that they're dead.
也改变不了我变成这样
Or that I became this.
-我们可以帮你  -用你的解药吗
- We can help you. - With your cure?
这里只有一种解药  闪电侠
There's only one cure for this, Flash.
死亡
Death.
大伙  我要坚持不住了
Guys, I can't keep this up.
诺拉  你需要再坚持一小会儿
Nora, you need to hang on for a little bit longer.
-你需要转弯  -富勒街的小巷
You're gonna turn on-- - The alleyway on Fuller.
在富勒街的小巷转弯  准备好
The alleyway on Fuller.Be ready.
准备什么
For what?
-我可不喜欢这样  -可不
- Ooh, I am not loving that. - Nope.
各位  我需要你俩去医院
Guys, we need you two at the hospital.
我们走
Let's go.
-那是什么玩意  -西斯科  怎么了
- What the hell was that? - Cisco, what happened?
不知道
I don't know.
我的缺口有点不对劲
Something's wrong with my breach.
我们不能穿过它了
We can't get through it!
我一直都想对付闪电侠
I've always wanted to be up against the Flash
和他的传奇小队
and his legendary team.
看来我最终没有错过一星半点
I guess I wasn't missing out on anything after all.
格蕾丝
Grace!
别这么做
Don't do this.
拜托
Please.
这不是让世界变得更好的正确方式
This isn't the way to make the world a better place.
你恨他们
You hated them.
我听了你的话
I heard you.
是我错了
I was wrong.
那种仇恨发酵成了更糟的东西
And that hate turned into something even worse.
我不该让你也这样想  格蕾西
It was wrong to make you feel that way, Gracie.
但你不需要走上和我一样的错路
But you don't have to go down the same path I did.
你不需要持有这种  这种愤怒
You don't have to hold on to this--this anger.
放手吧
Let it go.
但我父母
But my parents.
那是一场意外
It was an accident.
放手吧
Let it go.
在一切还来得及之前  别像我一样
Before it's too late, like it is for me.
你说的对  奥林叔叔
You're right, Uncle Orlin.
不
No!
为时已晚
It is too late.
救救我的格蕾丝
Save my Grace.
真不敢相信她杀了德怀尔
I can't believe she killed Dwyer.
是啊  就算是像德怀尔这样残忍的人
Yeah, as brutal as Dwyer was,
他对他侄女的爱总是能让他
his love for his niece always kept him
保留一些底线
from crossing certain lines.
格蕾丝不是这样的人
Not Grace.
没错  而且她的超能力很危险
No, and her powers are incredibly dangerous.
我在唐豪瑟站点时做了些测试
I ran some tests while I was at the Tannhauser offsite--
她的暗物质具有某种粘合功能
her dark matter has some sort of binding quality.
这能够让她在一定距离内
It allows her to telekinetically manipulate
遥控操作暗物质
dark matter within a certain proximity.
包括我们体内的暗物质
Including the dark matter in us?
我想是的
I think so.
我认为她和德怀尔超能力不同是因为
I think what makes her powers different from Dwyer's
她的能力源自脑中的伤口
is that they came from a wound in her head.
这是她这么强大的原因
That's why she's so much stronger.
诺拉怎么能看见格蕾丝当时所见的
How was Nora able to see what Grace was seeing?
诺拉和格蕾丝似乎心灵相通
Nora and Grace seem to be psychically connected.
我想是因为诺拉在
I think it's because of the time that Nora spent
格蕾丝脑中待过
in Grace's brain.
-有她的踪迹了吗  -没有
- Is there any sign of her? - No.
她绝对是神出鬼没的
She definitely ghosted.
薇琪和她的家人呢
What about Vickie and her family?
有联邦保护  他们会没事的
Uh, federal protection. They're gonna be fine.
我们说话这会儿他们就会得到新的身份
They're getting new identities as we speak.
我不知道你们怎么想
I don't know about anyone else,
但我想喝杯酒
but I could use a drink.
-这主意倒不错  -是啊  我加入
- Not a bad idea. - Yeah, I'm in.
-你想让我叫保姆吗  -是啊
- You want me to call a sitter? - Yeah.
西斯科  你想让卡米拉来吗
Cisco, you want to bring Kamilla?
这次不了
Not for this one.
诺拉  你要一起吗
Nora, you coming?
诺拉
Nora.
你想告诉我们些事  对吗
You want to tell us something, don't you?
她想告诉你们她的秘密
She wants to tell you her secret.
是吧
Right?
但她不知该从何说起
She doesn't know where to start.
当你的秘密威胁到身边的一切时
Difficult to know where to begin
要想知道从哪儿说起是很难的
when your secret threatens everything, everyone around you.
歇洛克  别说了
Sherloque, stop it.
或许可以从头说起
Maybe start at the beginning.
这是个很好的开始
It's a very good place to start.
你第一次穿越时间
When you first time-traveled.
小心谨慎  尽可能不留下足迹
So careful to leave the lightest footprint.
直到你突然做出了改变
Until you suddenly change course
在思考者卫星撞向地球时
and brazenly interfere with the Thinker satellite
公然干预
as it crashed to Earth.
我在心里想  不  不
I think to myself, "Nope, nope.
这种过头的行为根本说不通啊
This excessive action doesn't make sense."
直到最终明朗起来
Until you understand that...
那不是你的点子
it wasn't your idea.
求你  别说了
Please stop.
是有人指示你去做的
Someone instructed you to do it.
-别说了  -那个人的
- Stop. - Someone...
笔迹在你的日记本里
whose handwriting is in your journal.
笔迹检测
写着  "时间线是有延展性的"
Someone who wrote, "The timeline is malleable."
分析符号  翻译结果
时间线是有延展性的
尖端科研实验室时间球
和引导你这么久的是同一个人
Same person who's been directing you all this time,
分析笔迹中
匹配           成功
他在尝试着改变时间线
making puppets of all of us
来达到自己的目的时
as he seeks to alter the timeline
玩弄了我们所有人
to suit his own purpose.
艾尔伯德·斯旺
Eobard Thawne.
逆闪电  你的老师
The Reverse-Flash. Your teacher.
你的搭档
Your partner.
你的秘密
Your secret.
诺拉
Nora?
求你了  告诉我们这不是真的
Please tell us this isn't true.
她不能
She can't.
-爸爸  -因为这就是事实
- Dad... - Because it is true.
妈妈
Mom?
我想过要告诉你们
I wanted to tell you.
我有试着告诉你
I-I tried to tell you.
爸爸
Dad.
爸爸  不要
Dad, please!
爸爸
Dad!
我撒谎了  对不起
I'm sorry I lied to you!
我也很抱歉
So am I.
爸爸
Dad...